In any yoga practice, you can build internal heat and start to get slightly overheated just like any workout.
So it's important to know how to do cooling breath to keep yourself centered and keep you focus on the rest of your practice.
There's two ways you can do this.
One is holding the breath.
So take a nice breath in, and you could hold it for several seconds, maybe a count of two or three.
And then a nice breath out.
And repeat this several times.
So I could do it with you, inhale in, and hold your breath, and exhale and release the breath and let everything go.
This will slow the heart rate and it will also bring you back to center.
The other cooling breath is through a rolled tongue.
And some people can't roll their tongue, it's just a genetic difference.
But if you can roll your tongue, a nice way to do this is roll the tongue and breath out through the tongue like a straw.
So take a nice inhale in.
If you can't roll the tongue, another alternative, inhale through the nose, and when you exhale just let the tongue falls slightly out of the mouth and breath out of the mouth, letting out the internal heat.
And these are two great ways to cool yourself throughout the practice and find more focus.